Now we've all heard stories about those malicious cats.
You know, the little more evil ones.
Now, every feline is different but certainly there have been a couple that have given cats a bad name.
That said, drawing a malicious cat offers an excellent exercise in how different lines will very quickly change the features of our cat cartoons.
So here we have our happy cat.
Notice real quick the features, how we have the half circles with the rounded corner above.
Now with an evil cat, we're going to flip that around.
Basically going to have the top of the lines be flat, and then our circles underneath.
Now right away, I haven't drawn anything else, that does not look like the happiest of creature.
In this case, this creature is going to be a kitty.
So we draw on our triangular mouth there, and opposed to smiling, we're not going to have that evil of a cat, this cat is just frowning.
There will still be some whiskers, but they'll be close in.
It'll be a very narrow face.
Also, it's ears are going to be out a little further.
Almost kind of like horns.
The rest of the cat's body and posture are going to likewise be cold.
We're just going to have this cat's kind of be skulking and hulking like cats can do.
Bring out the claws there, it's tail is going to be up, maybe even waving a little bit, adding a couple of lines if you want to add the idea of motion.
Draw in some forepaws right there.
There you go.
And automatically, our cat looks angry.
This cat does not look happy, I would not want to meet it in a back alley.
And you can see, just with a little bit of manipulation of a lot of the lines we've already covered, how you can make a very happy feline look pretty angry at the world.